<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Elements of Eden]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Elements of Eden]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:05:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="http://res.cloudinary.com/hrscywv4p/image/upload/c_limit,h_540,w_720/yskj1rc61snj4txrkrrf.png">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/db3a71d7-84a0-48d2-bd10-0f505f280234/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">db3a71d7-84a0-48d2-bd10-0f505f280234</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="http://res.cloudinary.com/hrscywv4p/image/upload/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_140,w_140/k9uio5fxt6jsfv6lcvw0.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/d84878e8-7986-461b-a191-1cbc51b45010/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d84878e8-7986-461b-a191-1cbc51b45010</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>10. Start Seeds Indoors   Depending on what you want to plant and where you live, this advice might be too late (but you can try to play catchup or save it for next year!). Starting seeds indoors gives you a leg up on the growing season and is cheaper than buying starter plants. Previously mentioned All Things Plants will tell you when to start seeds indoors or plant them in the ground directly based on your area's last frost date. (While you're at it, convert coffee grounds into starter pots for planting, and be gentle with your seedlings by spritzing them instead of pouring water on them. They're just babies, after all. Protect them when you plant them outdoors with old paper towel rolls.)    Get Your Garden Started Now with This Indoor DIY Seed Starting Setup If you're thinking about starting a garden, it's not too early to plan for the warmer… Read more 9. Sharpen Your Tools   As with cooking tools, home improvement tools, and most other tools, the sharper the better. Get your pruning shears, shovels, and other tools in shape before you have to use them and you'll save time and effort in the long run. Even the lawn mower blade could use some sharpening and a tuneup. Bonus tip: Take care of your garden tools after each use and they'll stay in good shape for years to come.    How to Sharpen Your Garden and Workshop Tools Fall is a great time to take stock of your gardening and other bladed tools, and get them in… Read more workshop.​lifehacker.​com 8. Try Beginner Gardening Projects   What if you want to garden but don't know where to begin at all? Or have tried to but don't have a naturally green thumb? These starter ideas and resources, such as container gardening, can ease you into gardening successfully for the first or fiftieth time. Bag gardens in particular are not only low-effort, they overcome soil issues and help build soil for next year. Also, if you have kids, make sure to have them pitch in too. It's not only educational and fun, it might turn them into healthy eaters as well.    Learn to Grow Plants and Food With Beginner Garden Projects Maybe you've tried to "garden" before, but the results were brown, wilted, and… Read more 7. Get Your Soil Ready   Besides seeing your plants grow (and harvesting your vegetables, if you have a veggie garden), one of the most enjoyable aspects of gardening is buying the seeds or plantings and putting them in the soil. The manual labor of breaking up clods of soil, raking and aerating it? Not so much. But you have to get the soil ready before you plant. Gizmodo explains how to work the soil:  If last year's bumper crop has depleted your soil's nutrient content, you'll need to amend it before planting again. The process of amending soil involves adding materials in order to augment or modify the soil's physical characteristics. Sandy soils, for example, need amendments that increase its water and nutrient holding capacity, while clay soils need amendments that improve its aeration and porosity. Pick up a soil test kit from your local home improvement center to determine the plot's pH balance. This, in addition to the type of soil you have, determines the type of amenity you'll need. Make sure you bring a small bag of soil with you when you go to buy the kit and save yourself the return trip to buy the necessary amendments. Once you do have all the amendments you need, it's just a matter of digging up the top 6 to 12 inches of existing soil, thoroughly mixing the materials in, and then raking them level. It's like one big geeky science project! Mix coffee grounds into your soil while you're at it to deter slugs and other pests, as well as put a smile on acid-loving plants. If you're preparing a particularly weedy area for planting, try using a piece of cardboard to get rid of the weeds en masse or these DIY weed killers to keep weeds from sprouting.    Learn the Geeky Basics of Gardening Gardening may seem like a right-brain activity, full of contemplative moments and pretty flower… Read more 6. Make Compost to Supercharge Your Garden   Compost is the superfood for plants. You can turn food scraps, leaves, lawn clippings, and other otherwise useless "green waste" like these into nutrient-rich fertilizers and soil amendments for your plants. A compost bin powered by worms will produce compost in much less time than other kinds of the aerobic kind, but if you're not keen on being so close to a big bin of worms, you can create a compost tea instead, blend old food scraps for instant compost, or see if your community offers free compost (and mulch). After clearing the planting area and removing weeds, add a 4-inch layer of compost to new beds and work it well into the soil along with any other nutrients.    DIY Worm Compost Bin Worms can compost kitchen scraps and shredded paper much faster than the aerobic compost process… Read more 5. Prune Shrubs and Trees, and Divide Perennials   Winter is the best time to prune your trees and shrubs, before new growth and warm weather can increase the risk of disease. Just make sure you do it properly, lest you do irreparable damage to the tree or shrub. BHG says to prune fruit trees before buds begin to break into bloom, otherwise you could get a tinier crop due to stressing the tree. It's also a good time to divide perennials before plants have begun their spring growth.    Properly Prune Your Trees This Winter Winter is the best time of year to prune your trees. You have got the best visibility because the… Read more workshop.​lifehacker.​com 4. Choose New Plants Wisely   Plants need to be matched to the environment that they'll live in—the soil, lighting, and other climate conditions. Even the best gardeners probably couldn't make sun-loving plants like daisies thrive in the shade. The good news is many plants aren't too fussy. These are seven of the easiest vegetables to grow in your own yard, plants that don't need too much water, the kinds of plants that work equally well in sunny and shady places, and the vegetables that save you the most money for your effort. You might also consider the plants that grow best together. In general, to choose the right plant for the right place, think of the amount of sunlight the location gets, the soil moisture, and your area's hardiness zone. Tech tools like plant sensors can help optimize your garden as well.    The Seven Easiest Vegetables to Grow for Beginner Gardeners You don't need a green thumb to grow a bounty of fresh vegetables right in your backyard or… Read more 3. Know When to Plant and Harvest Them    The other things you should know about your new plant friends are how long they will take to grow, how big they will grow, and, if they are vegetables, when you can finally eat them. This chart offers an overview for many vegetables (northern hemisphere-specific). You can also use the Farmer's Almanac to find more information. As for other kinds of plants, you might not need to worry as much. Nurseries tend to stock plants when they're flowering, because that's when they're most appealing, so you can just walk in and buy what you like (and is appropriate for that spot to spruce up your outdoor space).    Everything You Need to Know About Vegetable Gardening in One Graphic Vegetable gardening is both an art and a science. Figuring out when and where to plant the… Read more 2. Create a Garden Layout That Works for You   Whether you have a small space but are dead set on growing 100 pounds of potatoes in those four square feet or have acres to work with, the best gardens start with a detailed plan. Previously mentioned Smart Gardener not only helps you diagram your garden or landscape, it can recommend a garden plan based on your selected plants and location, along with a personalized gardening to do list and other intelligent features.    Grow 100 lbs. of Potatoes in 4 Square Feet Potatoes seem like the kind of plant you'd need a substantial garden for—the kind your… Read more If you're short on space (and/or love symmetry), a square foot garden might be for you; this raised bed garden dedicates 1x1 square foot plots to specific plants and can be cost-effective. On the other hand, rounded edges could get you more planting space. We've also showcased several vertical and other small space gardens over the years, from the shoe organizer herb garden and this shipping pallet version to the simple salad in a box.    Build a Square Foot Garden If you'd love to plant your own kitchen garden but don't really have the yard space or… Read more 1. Calibrate and Automate Your Garden   Finally, gardening is a fun hobby, but it's also hard work at times. Make it a little easier on yourself with some gardening hacks. For example, calibrate sprinklers so they always water your lawn just right (which means, as little as possible, conserving water). Build a drip irrigation system so you never forget to water your garden, or make an automatic plant watering systems using plastic bags. If you're container gardening, you can make EarthBox-like self-watering planters. Or, even better, get your container garden to not only water itself but also tweet you when it needs a water refill. Gardens are so high-tech these days.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/10-start-seeds-indoors-depending-on-what-you-want-to-plan/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">dec131d8-2ea4-4e5f-be1e-58a04ceec829</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="http://res.cloudinary.com/hrscywv4p/image/upload/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_140,w_140/xyyuvxrcauqwu4c1wbvz.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/f4277fb2-6b29-4efc-8c0e-d16aaecac195/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f4277fb2-6b29-4efc-8c0e-d16aaecac195</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>CUSTOM DESIGNED JUST FOR YOU Some of our most memorable moments are times spent with family and friends around a fire pit or barbeque. Let us custom design a space that lends itself to your style of entertaining.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/custom-designed-just-for-you-some-of-our-most-memorable-mome/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e5e4d568-dcd6-4050-919b-b8a086d89f44</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="http://res.cloudinary.com/hrscywv4p/image/upload/c_limit,h_900,w_1200/k9uio5fxt6jsfv6lcvw0.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/about-elements-of-eden-elements-of-eden-provides-solutions/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4c476998-03ac-4fb2-ab36-757d3044b901</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 18:03:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 10 Ways to Get Your Dream Garden Ready This Year]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Top 10 Ways to Get Your Dream Garden Ready This Year</h1><p>Believe it or not, winter is ending soon, which means the time is ripe to get our plans in order for this year's garden, whether you're dreaming of a bounty of vegetables, a balcony of colorful flowers, or some other sort of outdoor oasis. </p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/90d309fc28695bb2c35be2941ffe83cd30468f7d.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://lifehacker.com/top-10-ways-to-get-your-dream-garden-ready-this-year-1691415272</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9656cc98-db81-462a-ad6a-1fecf9d3640b</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hardscapes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Hardscapes</h1><p>Experience the 'Outdoors' in a new way with our custom hardscapes..</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/2b95acabe22521a379fe687cb3c57f57df0cb801.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/elements-of-eden/66faab6f-9f12-493e-ad76-80c1e3f4eba1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">66faab6f-9f12-493e-ad76-80c1e3f4eba1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:37:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>